Mohammed Mohaiminul Haque

Proficient in multiple programming languages, with experience that was gained through coursework, projects, online courses and internships. This includes concepts related to Security, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, OOP, Algorithms, Data Science, Database Management and Data Structures. I have attended several hackathons and in one of them I won the prize for solving one of the most complex question from Heriot Watt University, Dubai. Acquire qualities of a responsible leader, an excellent programmer and a well rounded team player who is open for discussion.

mhaque1@ualberta.ca



+1 7802897241



in linkedin.com/in/mohaimin-haque-a0b59923a



github.com/TheOnly1Lion

EDUCATION

BSc in Computing Science w/ Specialization University of Alberta

08/2020 - Present

Edmonton, Canada

Awards and Scholarships

University of Alberta

Scholarships

- University of Alberta International Country Scholarship 2020-2021 - University of Alberta International Scholarship 2020-2021

SKILLS



Game Development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern

Canadian University Dubai

01/2019 - 01/2019

Dubai United Arab Emirates

- Selected from high-school to intern in this university and help them
- Task was to code a robot's moves and functionalities with actuators and sensors.
- Robots were programmed using Lego Mindstorm EV3 that used C programming language

Virtual Intern

Data Glacier

08/2022 - 08/2022

(Remote) Uttar Pradesh, India

- Role
- Unpaid internship where they go through the stages of Data Science with projects and working on databases.
- Worked under the Data and Analytics division to process data using python and pushing to Github.
- Had to make reports on the status of each tests on the data and upload it on Canvas portal

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Meal Plan app (09/2022 - Present)

 Mobile application using Android Studio and scrum framework to store food storage, recipes, meals, and shopping lists into firestore. Uses git version control and includes git user stories, workflow and milestones for progress status. (Java)

Database project (10/2021 - 11/2021)

Exporting excel and json files using python to set it up on MongoDB Servers and query it according to the specifications.(Python and SQL)

Classifying MNIST images (03/2022)

Classifying MNIST images using a convolutional neural network that includes testing sets to evaluate accuracy of the training sets with hidden layers.

Keylogger app (10/2022 - Present)

An app that can act as a keylogger for a phone and update the keystrokes to the Firestore database.(Java)

Alphabetical Word Game App (08/2022)

An alphabetic word and questionnaire game made using android studio. (Java)

Ceaser Cipher Encoder (10/2020)

An encryption and decryption tool on python. Encrypts user entered text based on the entered key by adding symbols and shifts using Hash functions and values. Decrypts keys based on the characters and symbols used

OUALIFICATIONS

Programming Languages

C, Python, Java, SQL, Jupyter, Julia, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Operating Systems

Microsoft Windows, MacOS, Virtualization

Networking

Wireshark, OSI Model, REST API

Protocols

HTTP, FTP, SSH,UDP,TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, LAN, WAN,SMTP

CERTIFICATES

The Complete Splunk Beginner Course 2022 expected January 2023

Fundamentals of OT Cybersecurity (ICS/SCADA)

expected January 2023

BCS Award (Herriot Watt Dubai) (02/2019)

Award for solving BCS programming question